（マイト･ガイ）
あっ お前 まさか…
Don't tell me you're...
（干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめ）
思い出したようですね
It appears that you've remembered...
Have we met before...?
俺と会ったことがあるのか？
珍獣は頭のほうも
獣レベルのようですね
It looks like the freak beast's intelligence
is at the level of a beast too...
Well... I'll make you remember soon...
まあ すぐに思い出させて
差し上げますがね
（うずまきナルト）んっ
Itachi...
（チヨ）イタチ
（ナルト）ん？
Ah, so he is that brat...
who killed his entire clan.
（チヨ）ほう こヤツが…
あの一族 皆殺しのガキかの
It's been a while, Kakashi-san, Naruto-kun...
（うちはイタチ）久しぶりですね
カカシさん ナルト君
A Sharingan...
Just like Sasuke-kun's!
（春野はるのサクラ）
サスケ君と同じ写輪眼(しゃりんがん)
この人が サスケ君とナルトを
苦しめてる人
He is the... one who's tormenting
Sasuke-kun and Naruto.
You bastard...
（ナルト）こんにゃろ
俺だけじゃなく我愛羅があらまで
Not just me, but Gaara too!
俺がお前ら ぶっ潰す！
I will destroy you guys!
（はたけカカシ）あっ
Everyone! Don't look directly
at his eyes! It's dangerous!
みんな あいつの目を直接 見るな
危険だ！
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
～♪
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
A Meeting
with Destiny
So this is the Akatsuki!
（日向ひゅうがネジ）これが暁あかつきか
（鬼鮫）フフフフッ…
Water Style:
Exploding Water Shock Wave!
水遁すいとん･爆水衝波ばくすいしょうは！
He's coming!
くるぞ
（ロック･リー）はい
Yes!
ハハハハッ…
Here I go!
いきますよ
（テンテン）あっ
Itachi's Genjutsu is Visual Jutsu.
（カカシ）イタチの幻術は瞳術どうじゅつ
Therefore, it's a type where one gets
caught by his sight,
つまりは 視覚ではめるタイプだ
so it'll be okay as long as we don't make
eye contact with him.
目さえ合わせなければ オーケーだ
Yeah, I know!
ああ 分かってるって
But then...
でも それじゃあ
How should we fight him?
どうやって戦えば…
Well...
（カカシ）それは…
Guy, how did you fight with Itachi?
ガイ お前
イタチとどうやり合った？
Huh?
（ガイ）うん？
それはな…
Well...
Decipher his actions just by how
he moves his body and feet.
（カカシ）体や足の動きだけで
ヤツの行動を判断するんだ
それって かなり難しいような…
That seems pretty hard.
The Uchiha clan, eh?
うちは一族か
写輪眼しゃりんがんを相手にするのは
久しぶりじゃがの
It's been a while since
I went up against a Sharingan.
（ナルト）あっ
そう驚嘆することもない
You don't have to be that surprised.
There are a few fighting techniques
to counter this Visual Jutsu.
この瞳術とやり合うには
いくつかの戦術がある
あ… どうすりゃいいんだ
What should we do?
"If it's one against one,
then you must flee."
１対１なら必ず逃げる
"If it's two against one,
then take the back."
２対１なら 後ろを取れじゃ
Say what?
なんだ？ それ
You know what "if it's one against one,
then flee" means right?
１対１なら必ず逃げろは 分かるな
There is no way you can win.
まず 勝ち目はないということじゃ
But if it's two against one...
じゃが ２対１なら…
If it's two against one,
２対１なら
１人が幻術にかけられても
even if one is caught by the Genjutsu,
the other will take his back and hit him.
もう１人が あやつの後ろを取り
本体をたたけば 幻術は解ける
Then the Genjutsu will cease.
Even if that is impossible,
たとえ それが無理でも
if you hit your teammate,
then you can end the Genjutsu.
仲間をどつけば
幻術を解いてやることもできる
つまり こちらが複数なら
So, if there is more than one of us,
then one will distract him.
１人が陽動ようどう
そのほかは
写輪眼の死角になる後ろから
The rest of us will constantly
attack him from the back
where the Sharingan can't see.
常に攻める手だ
I see.
なるほど
さすが
Amazing, you know a lot from old age!
年 食ってるだけあるってばよ
じゃあ 俺が後ろ…
Then I'll take his back--
Wait!
（カカシ）待て
（ナルト）あっ
（鬼鮫）ウヘヘヘ…
ネジ！　リー！
Neji! Lee!
So... how is it?
さあ どうです？
（ガイ）おっ！
（鬼鮫）思い出しませんか？
Doesn't it remind you?!
How can he let out this much water?
こんなに大量の水を出せるなんて
すさまじいまでの
膨大なチャクラ量があって
This technique requires
a huge amount of Chakra.
初めてなせる技だ
Kakashi-sensei,
what do you mean by wait?!
カカシ先生
“待て”って
どういうことだってばよ
Do you want to say my way of fighting
the Sharingan is wrong?
わしの写輪眼に対する戦術
間違っとるとでも言いたいのか
That would work
if it's an ordinary Genjutsu,
まあ ただの現実レベルなら
そうなんですが
but it's a bit more complicated
in his case.
もう少しやっかいでしてね
こいつの場合は
What?
なんじゃ？
He uses Mangekyo Sharingan
万華鏡写輪眼まんげきょうしゃりんがんという...
which is a much stronger Visual Jutsu
than an ordinary Sharingan.
本来の写輪眼よりも
強力な瞳術を使います
If you receive his Visual Jutsu,
その瞳術を食らえば
then you will experience
his Genjutsu in a second.
ほんの一瞬で ヤツの現実を
体感することになります
In other words, even though it may seem
like a second to others,
つまり 周りから見れば
一瞬の間でも
the person who receives the Jutsu
will feel it for hours or days.
術を食らったものは 数時間…
あるいは
数日にも感じられるんです
In my case, I roamed around in
his Jutsu for three days,
現に 私はヤツの術中に
丸３日間 さまよい
and lost consciousness
for more than a week.
１週間以上も
意識を失ってしまいました
It's not a matter of ending
or not ending the Genjutsu.
現実を 解く解かないの
話ではありませんよ
He's troublesome...
Who exactly is this guy?
（チヨ）やっかいなヤツじゃ
こヤツ 一体 何者じゃ？
Impressive, Kakashi-san.
さすが カカシさんだ
It seems you didn't suffer
my Tsukiyomi, Nightmare Realm, in vain.
１度 私の月読つくよみを
食らっているだけのことはある
That is not all that I know...
分かってるのは
それだけじゃないよ
After you used the Visual Jutsu,
you were quite exhausted
お前は あの瞳術を使用したあと
かなり疲労し
戦いを すぐ治めて
立ち去ろうとした
and you ended the battle immediately
and tried to leave.
しかし イタチさん
But Itachi-san...
Even for you, it is dangerous
to use that "eye" too much...
その目を使いすぎるのは
あなたにとっても危険
We did not come here to fight.
俺たちは戦争しに来たんじゃない
残念だが これ以上はナンセンスだ
Unfortunately, anything more than
this is nonsense. Let's go.
帰るぞ
In addition to using up quite
a lot of Chakra,
（カカシ）
あれは かなりのチャクラを
必要とするうえに
it seems it comes with some risk
to your "eye" as well, Itachi.
お前の目にとっても なんらかの
重いリスクを伴うようだな
イタチ
From just one match,
you have analyzed it quite well.
たった１度の手合わせで
よく分析している
Itachi.
イタチよ
Your eyesight...
How much has it weakened?
お前の視力…
どこまで落ちている？
（イタチ）んっ！
Kakashi-san... Could it be that you...?
カカシさん
あなた まさか…
Where is he?
あいつはどこです？
あっ！
Guy-sensei! Tenten!
ガイ先生！　テンテン！
あっ！
ハッハハハ…
くっ
（鬼鮫）うらあ！
（ガイ）ハハッ
くうっ
A Water Clone!
水分身みずぶんしんか
You didn't even have time to recall.
思い出す暇もありませんでしたね
ヘッヘヘヘ…
It seems like Itachi also has come
into contact with the enemy...
（暁リーダー）
イタチも敵と接触したようだな
Kisame is in the middle of a fight.
鬼鮫は戦闘中か
ハッハハ…
ふんっ！
Lee!
リー
Leaf Rising Wind!
（リー）木こノ葉は昇風しょうふう！
What?!
何！
8 Trigrams: Air Palm!
八卦空掌はっけくうしょう！
（鬼鮫）おっ！
It's programmed.
仕込み
クソ！ 逃がした
Damn! I let him get away!
Where did he go?
ヤツはどこへ行った？
Neji, where's the enemy's location?
ネジ 敵の位置は？
In front! He's coming up.
正面だ 上がってくるぞ
I found him!
見つけました
Seriously... What troublesome brats.
（鬼鮫）全く…
やっかいなガキどもですね
It's so bothersome.
面倒くさい
はっ 水遁系忍術に そのでかい刀
The Water Style Ninjutsu
and that big sword...
You are...!
お前は…
（鬼鮫）どうやら やっと
思い出していただけたようですね
It seems like you have
finally remembered.
I do feel like we have met somewhere.
どこかで会ったような気も…
（テンテン）うう…
You still can't remember, huh...
まだ思い出せないんですね
You really are good
at hurting people's feelings.
本当に 人の気を逆なでするのが
お上手ですね
Until you recall...
思い出すまで…
I will take my time putting you
through pain.
じっくり いたぶってあげましょう
I underestimated you back then.
But I'm not that pathetic.
（カカシ）まあ
この前は油断しちゃったけどね
俺も そうダサくはないよ
（サクラ）あっ
It's not going to work
the way it did before, you see.
（カカシ）前回と同じようには
いかないんだなあ これが
ふっ
It's a huge mistake if you think
I'm the same as before!
この俺も 前回と同じだと思ったら
大間違いだってばよ
Naruto, I'll deal with him.
（カカシ）
ナルト こいつは俺がやる
（ナルト）ん？
This happened before too.
（ナルト）
こんなこと 確か前にも…
（カカシ）お前ら 卍まんじの陣だ
Form the Manji.
You guys look after Tazuna-san.
タズナさんを守れ
Don't get involved in the fight.
お前たちは戦いに加わるな
Huh?
（サクラ）えっ
（カカシ）
それが ここでのチームワークだ
And work as a team here.
Y-You mean another
non-fighting teamwork?
また…
また戦わない
チームワークってやつかよ！
No. This time, cover me.
いいや 今回は援護を頼む
あっ
To be honest, I want to be cool
and say, "Go on ahead", but...
本当は格好つけて 先を急げと
言いたいところなんだけどね
Against him,
even I can't contain him alone.
俺も こいつ相手じゃ
１人で押さえきれない
んっ
さてと
Let's see...
（ガイ）さあ 反撃開始だ
It's time for a counterattack.
First, I'll get him off guard.
まず 俺がヤツの隙を作る
隙ができたら迷わず打て
If I succeed, don't hesitate to attack.
- Roger!
（３人）了解
そんな簡単に隙を見せると
お思いですか
Do you think you'll get me
off guard that easily?
その考え すぐにでも
改めさせてあげますよ
I will quickly change your mind.
Gentle Fist!
（ネジ）柔拳じゅうけん！
（鬼鮫）うっ
あっ
ぐわっ！
ハッハハハ…
I see...
なるほど
You swing that heavy sword so easily
and you don't get caught off guard.
あんな大きな刀を軽々と振り回し
なかなか隙を見せてくれませんね
接近戦がダメなら…
If close battle does not work...
How's that?
これでどう？
フハハハ…
Did you do something?
何かしましたか？
んっ やっかいな刀ね
What an annoying sword.
そうか その刀…
Oh yeah, that sword...!
Did you recall?
（鬼鮫）思い出しましたか
（ガイ）それが お前の武器か
That's your weapon, huh?
見れば分かる
You can tell by looking.
But there is a big difference
between knowing it
だが はっきり分かるのと
そうでないのとは
and really knowing it.
大きな違いがあるのだ
さすがはガイ先生
As expected Guy-sensei...
Each word holds a deep meaning.
言葉の１つ１つ 奥が深いですね
Why now for god's sake?
Can you quit being amazed every time?
何をいまさら
毎回のこのノリも なんとかしてよ
Forget it, Tenten.
（ネジ）諦めろ テンテン
Let me take back what I said.
前言を撤回させてもらいますよ
頭のレベルは獣以下のようですね
It seems like your intelligence
is less than an animal.
いくぞ！
Here we go!
ダイナミックアクション！
Dynamic action!
（イタチ）そろそろ
一緒に来てもらうことにするよ
It's about time for you to come with me...
Naruto.
ナルト君
うくっ う…
I'll go first!
（カカシ）まずは 俺だ
うっ！
影分身かげぶんしん
Shadow Clone?!
はあああー！
Rasengan!
螺旋丸らせんがん！
This is also a Shadow Clone!
（ナルト）こいつも 影分身
ん？
あっ
（サクラ）う… うっ うう…
あっ サクラちゃん
Sakura-chan! Granny!
ばあちゃん
（チヨ）うう…
（サクラ）うっ…
Sakura...chan...?
サクラ… ちゃん
あっ
んっ
（鬼鮫）ううっ！
Now!
今だ！
ちっ
水分身の術
Water Clone Jutsu!
何！
What?!
あっ！
（リー）ああっ
（ネジ）うっ
あっ
水牢すいろうの術！
Water Prison Jutsu!
（ネジ）なあっ
しまった
Damn it!
とあっ！
（水しぶきの音）
（ガイ）だあっ！
だあ～！
（ネジ）ぐ… ぐあっ
あっ ああ…
Lee! Neji! Tenten!
リー！　ネジ！　テンテン！
（テンテン）ぐっ くう…
（ネジ）あ…
（リー）あ…
（カカシ）うっ ああ…
Kakashi-sensei!
（ナルト）カカシ先生
うっ
What's going on?
どうなってるんだってばよ
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
Hello kids, thanks for coming to
the Kisame aquarium today.
よい子のみんな
きょうは 鬼鮫水族館に
来てくれてありがとね
お待ちかね 当館のアイドル...
The show you've been waiting for
is about to begin.
リーダーのサメオ君 率いる
５匹のサメ君たちと
The five sharks led by this aquarium's
fabulous leader
ガイお兄さんの
迫力満点のショーが始まります
Shark Boy and Brother Guy.
その前に 注意点
Before that, here are some warnings.
前のほうのお友達は
水しぶきに注意してね
Those in the front row should
watch out for the water splash.
じゃあ みんな 大きな声で呼ぶよ
Okay everyone;
let's yell as loud as we can.
はい せ～の
Okay ready, Shark Boy!
サメオく～ん！
Naruto's Growth
Next time: "Naruto's Growth"
次回
「ナルトの成長」
Notable People in the Leaf Village
This section is going to introduce
the famous people of the village.
里の有名人を紹介する
このコーナー
Today's guest is Leaf Village's
most passionate teacher.
きょうのゲストは
木ノ葉一の熱血教師
The person I admire the most!
Guy-sensei!
僕が最も尊敬するお方
ガイ先生です
Dynamic Entry!
（ガイ）
ダイナミックエントリー！
ってことで
Well, hello, I am The Noble Blue Beast
of the Leaf Village, Might Guy!
どうも 木ノ葉の気高き碧あおい猛獣
マイト･ガイだ
Excuse me for the sudden question,
Guy-sensei, but what is youth?
いきなりですが ガイ先生
青春とはなんですか？
The overflowing of sweat and tears
and a little tint of passion.
（ガイ）あふれ出す汗と涙と
さりげない熱血
It's ecstasy that only those who
work hard will attain, that is Youth!
努力した者だけが得られる
エクスタシー
それが青春だ！
I see, a tint of passion, huh?
なるほど
さりげない熱血ですね
Another thing that is important is
to have a rival that you can compete with.
（ガイ）
それと もう１つ大事なのは
互いに 切磋琢磨せっさたくまし合える
ライバルの存在だ
That's Kakashi-sensei, right?
（リー）カカシ先生ですね
That's right. People call us
the everlasting rivals.
（ガイ）
そうだ 人は俺たちのことを
永遠のライバルと呼ぶ
Of course, I'm winning
with 51 wins and 50 losses.
まあ 51勝50敗で
俺が勝ち越しているがな
It's amazing that you
won against Kakashi-sensei! Guy-sensei!
（リー）カカシ先生に勝つなんて
さすがは ガイ先生
I will follow you
to the ends of the earth!
どこまでも ついていきますよ
おう リーよ
Oh Lee!
（リー･ガイ）青春バンザーイ！
— Hurray for adolescence!
（リー）熱あちっ 熱っ…
（ガイ）うおっ 熱っ…
— Hot!
T
o
b
e
c
o
n
t
i
n
u
e
d
.
（リー･ガイ）
熱あちっ 熱っ 熱っ…